# Steven Ott Software Developer

Madison, WI · (920) 286-1509 · stevenott@charter.net · stuott.github.io

#### **About**

Software developer with two years of experience working on the cardiology application team at Epic Systems, designing and implementing workflows for clinicians at large-scale healthcare systems. Demonstrates the ability to create high-quality software solutions that are responsive to complex customer issues while meeting quarterly release timelines.

#### **Skills**

HTML · SASS/CSS · JavaScript/TypeScript · React · .NET/C# · Caché · C++ · Python Git · Visual Studio · VS Code · Project Management · Code/Design Review · Testing Procedures

## **Experience**

#### Software Developer

June 2022 - Present

Epic Systems Verona, WI

- Investigated and implemented fixes for existing functional issues by collaborating with an interdisciplinary team of developers, testers, and customer-facing roles
- Enhanced workflows for clinicians working in procedural specialties by reducing required clicks and consolidating documentation tools
- Reviewed proposed code changes and designs from other developers to ensure proper code quality and prevent issues in cross-app functionality
- Supported a team of forty developers through a transition from SVN to Git version control by completing additional troubleshooting training and holding daily office hours
- Traveled to customer sites to aid end-users as they installed a new cardiology application as well as gain an understanding of their work environment and challenges

## Software Engineering Intern

May 2021 - August 2021

Plexus Corp Neenah, WI

- Developed software updates for embedded systems used by medical device manufacturers
  Evaluated existing product requirements and created software verification test procedures to
- Evaluated existing product requirements and created software verification test procedures to provide a reliable quality standard for an integrated system
- Improved development workflows by migrating source code repositories from SVN to Git and creating project-specific virtual environment configurations

## Optometric Technician

May 2020 - August 2020

Your Eye Care Team

New Holstein, WI

- Coordinated with a team to efficiently perform comprehensive eye health examinations and provide high-level medical eye care
- Assisted optometrists by completing pre-exam testing for visual acuity and eye health
- Maintained proper HIPAA procedures and security guidelines to safeguard patient confidentiality

### **Education**

Michigan Technological University

**September 2018 - May 2022** 

BS Computer Engineering · 3.93 GPA · Dean's List